<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ice Giant Systems 2020 on Ice Giant Systems 2020</title>
    <link>https://ice-giants.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ice Giant Systems 2020 on Ice Giant Systems 2020</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 20:22:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>First Announcement</title>
      <link>https://ice-giants.github.io/post/first-announcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 20:22:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ice-giants.github.io/post/first-announcement/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;first-announcement-ice-giant-systems-2020&#34;&gt;First Announcement:  Ice Giant Systems 2020.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;january-20th-22nd-2020-royal-society-london&#34;&gt;January 20th-22nd 2020, Royal Society, London.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New and ambitious missions to the distant Ice Giants and their satellites will become a key element of our Solar System exploration in the coming decades.  The planetary community is warmly invited to attend an international conference on Ice Giant exploration at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://royalsociety.org/science-events-and-lectures/for-scientists/]&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Royal Society in London&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;format&#34;&gt;Format:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The meeting will consist of two days of invited plenary talks and a third day of splinter workshops, aiming to showcase the cutting edge of Ice Giant system research and the rationale for a return to Uranus and Neptune.  Plenaries and splinter workshops will be summarised in a special issue of &lt;a href=&#34;https://royalsocietypublishing.org/journal/rsta&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society A&lt;/a&gt; (one of the world’s oldest scientific journals, dating to the 1660s), reviewing state-of-the-art knowledge of the Ice Giant Systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;funding&#34;&gt;Funding:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plenary discussion meeting is free to attend, sponsored by the Royal Society.  A small fee will be levied for the splinter meetings.  The early announcement of the meeting date should allow contributors to seek funding for travel and accommodation in London – US participants might consider the &lt;a href=&#34;https://aas.org/grants-and-prizes/international-travel-grants&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;AAS international travel grant&lt;/a&gt; program (deadline in June 2019); UK participants could look to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ras.ac.uk/awards-and-grants/conferencemeeting-travel-subsistence&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Royal Astronomical Society travel grants&lt;/a&gt; (deadline in August 2019).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;registration-and-abstracts&#34;&gt;Registration and Abstracts:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A second announcement will be circulated when the registration and abstract submission portals are open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best wishes on behalf of the #IceGiants2020 Science Organising Committee:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leigh Fletcher, Adam Masters, Ian Cohen, Amy Simon, Mark Hofstadter, Athena Coustenis, Chris Arridge, Kathleen Mandt, Diego Turrini, Laurent Lamy, David Atkinson, Pontus Brandt, Olivier Witasse, Olivier Mousis, and Abigail Rymer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ice Giant Media Coverage</title>
      <link>https://ice-giants.github.io/post/ice-giant-media-coverage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 20:21:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ice-giants.github.io/post/ice-giant-media-coverage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;twitter-moment&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/i/moments/1108817515877224456?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;Media Coverage: Missions to the Ice Giants&lt;/a&gt; &lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Entry Probes Meeting</title>
      <link>https://ice-giants.github.io/post/marseille-in-situ-probes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 21:35:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ice-giants.github.io/post/marseille-in-situ-probes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;twitter-moment&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/i/moments/1101145137814614016?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;In Situ Exploration of the Ice Giants&lt;/a&gt; &lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COSPAR Ice Giants 2018</title>
      <link>https://ice-giants.github.io/post/cospar-ice-giants-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 21:50:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ice-giants.github.io/post/cospar-ice-giants-2018/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cospar-symposium-b5-4-wednesday-july-18th-2018&#34;&gt;COSPAR Symposium B5.4 – Wednesday July 18th 2018&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ice-giant-systems-new-results-and-future-exploration&#34;&gt;Ice Giant Systems:  New Results and Future Exploration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MSO: Leigh Fletcher (Univ. of Leicester)
DSO:   Amy Simon (Goddard Spaceflight Center)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;COSPAR sub-commission B5 hosted several symposia focussing on the exploration of the outer solar system at the 2018 COSPAR meeting in Pasadena, ranging from the highlights of past missions (Cassini), active missions (Juno), and future missions (exploration of ocean worlds).  The ice giant community met on Wednesday afternoon to focus on the exploration of Uranus and Neptune, from their interiors, to their atmospheres, magnetospheres, rings and satellite systems.  Unusual for the COSPAR symposia, the organisers split the time between standard oral presentations and a workshop-style discussion forum on international collaboration for a future ice giant mission.  Both sections were well received and fostered interesting discussions between conference delegates for the remainder of the COSPAR meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;new-scientific-results&#34;&gt;New Scientific Results&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ice giants, Uranus and Neptune, have been visited only once by a robotic spacecraft (Voyager 2 in 1986 and 1989, respectively).  Many of the most recent insights into how these unusual systems work are therefore the result of Earth-based observations, both from ground-based observatories and space telescopes. Hoftstadter et al. contrasted radio-wave observations of Saturn and Uranus from facilities like the Very Large Array (VLA), explaining how spectral models are used to explore the deep abundances of ammonia, hydrogen sulphide and (potentially) water within these worlds.  The existing Uranus data sensing the atmospheric composition can be explained by approximately solar abundances of these heavy materials, raising the question of how the materials might be trapped within their deeper interiors.  Wong et al. described Hubble Space Telescope observations of a new dark oval that formed on Neptune in 2015, not dissimilar from the Great Dark Spot observed by Voyager in 1989.  This oval has been re-observed several times since 2015 as it drifted southwards, whereas most drift equatorward.  Its bright companion clouds have become more centred within the vortex, and Wong’s team plans to track its continued evolution in the coming years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Observations at mid-infrared wavelengths, sensing the atmospheric temperatures and composition of Uranus and Neptune, featured significantly for the rest of the symposium, largely as a result of preparation for the expected slew of data from the James Webb Space Telescope, due for launch in 2021.  Orton et al. presented images of Uranus at wavelengths sensing stratospheric emission from acetylene gas.  This provides a capability inaccessible to Voyager – the ability to probe the circulation of Uranus’ stratosphere.  The results, from the Very Large Telescope (VLT) and Gemini Observatory, indicate an unusual circulation pattern that localises the stratospheric emission to Uranus’ poles at the time of the 2007 equinox.  Fletcher et al. followed this up in a subsequent talk using spatially-resolved mid-infrared spectroscopy of Uranus, which is extremely challenging from Earth but whets the appetite for future data from the MIRI 5-28 µm instrument on JWST, which will provide the first
spatially-resolved spectra at these wavelengths.  Fletcher also presented VLT observations of Neptune, characterising stratospheric temperatures within its warm polar vortex during Neptune’s southern summertime conditions.  Sinclair et al. presented further stratospheric imaging of Neptune from the VLT, correlating diffuse warm regions in the stratosphere with cloud activity observed in the troposphere.  Finally, a poster by Rowe-Gurney et al. explored longitudinal variability observed in Spitzer Space Telescope disc-averaged spectra of Uranus, but not Neptune, hinting at unexpected dynamic variability on a world usually thought of as stagnant and inactive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scientific presentations continued with Masters et al. explaining how the processes governing ice giant magnetospheres might be rather different from those at work on the gas giants, presenting models indicating the important role of a viscous-like interaction between the solar wind and the magnetosphere.  Kirchoff et al. contrasted impact cratering size distributions on the Uranian satellites with those on Jupiter and Saturn, advocating future exploration of these terrains.  And Mandt et al. concluded the scientific discussion by exploring how measurements of the deuterium and nitrogen content of Triton’s atmosphere could prove crucial in understanding the origin of volatiles on distant worlds, including Pluto.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;future-exploration&#34;&gt;Future Exploration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final hour of the symposium shifted into a discussion of future international collaboration on missions to the ice giants, hosted by Hoftstadter, Simon and Fletcher.  Hofstadter reported the primary outcomes of the 2016-17 NASA-ESA Science Definition Team study, which concluded in 2017 with an extensive report (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lpi.usra.edu/icegiants/mission_study/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.lpi.usra.edu/icegiants/mission_study/&lt;/a&gt;).  Simon described a recent white paper advocating a two-mission concept, combining a Uranus flyby with a KBO mission, alongside a dedicated Neptune-Triton orbital mission (&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1807.08769&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://arxiv.org/abs/1807.08769&lt;/a&gt;).  It was stressed that this was one of many potential ice giant exploration strategies, and concepts for Uranus orbital exploration were also discussed.  There was discussion of the criticality of planetary entry probes (&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1708.00235&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://arxiv.org/abs/1708.00235&lt;/a&gt;), combined with orbital remote sensing in the infrared and microwave, in order to explore the chemical composition of Uranus and Neptune for comparisons with other targets in the solar system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several ideas were raised during the wide-ranging discussion, including the need to identify and develop key enabling technologies for future ice giant missions, and how to ensure that ice giant science remained at the top of the agenda in the US Decadal Survey, ESA’s Cosmic Vision, and within the sites of other space agencies.  Particular attention focussed on how to open up the US medium-class missions (New Frontiers) to allow for ice giant exploration and on starting a new large-class mission before the next Decadal review.  Given the breadth of ideas, and the timescale for the next US decadal and future potential ESA studies, it was suggested that a dedicated ice giant workshop be held in 2019, to be used as a focal point for the development of topical white papers.  The discussion section was warmly received, and we would encourage similar events be worked into the programme for future COSPAR symposia.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exoplanets in our Backyard</title>
      <link>https://ice-giants.github.io/post/exoplanets-ice-giants/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 21:30:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ice-giants.github.io/post/exoplanets-ice-giants/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;exoplanet-science-strategy-white-paper&#34;&gt;Exoplanet Science Strategy White Paper&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1804.03573&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Rymer et al., 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ice-giants/papers/blob/master/2018rymer_exoplanets.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Link to white paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Submitted to the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering and Medicine, Space Studies Board&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Future remote sensing of exoplanets will be enhanced by a thorough investigation of our solar system Ice Giants (Neptune-size planets). What can the configuration of the magnetic field tell us (remotely) about the interior, and what implications does that field have for the structure of the magnetosphere; energy input into the atmosphere, and surface geophysics (for example surface weathering of satellites that might harbour sub-surface oceans). How can monitoring of auroral emission help inform future remote observations of emission from exoplanets? Our Solar System provides the only laboratory in which we can perform in-situ experiments to understand exoplanet formation, dynamos, systems and magnetospheres.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within the past decade it has been realized that Neptune-size planets are among the most common class of exoplanet in our galaxy, [Fulton et al., 2017].  In situ study of an Ice Giant will enable numerous investigations that, despite several decades of study, are still not fully understood. These include the following top-level questions that have direct relevance to exoplanets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Auroral configuration and emission - unlike our Solar System, eccentric and
complex orbital characteristics appear to be common in other planetary systems, so that the understanding of radio emission produced by Uranus could have profound importance for interpreting future radio detections of exoplanets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Magnetospheric Transport/Atmospheric Energy Deposition - mechanisms for plasma transport and diffusion, that are well understood at other planets, have never been studied in this type of geometry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Radiation Belts (Energetic Particle Trapping) - how stable are the Uranian radiation belts? Are they always present? Can we guide the search for exoplanets with magnetic fields by identifying which of them have radiation belts?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bulk Composition and Internal Structure - understanding the composition and structure of our Solar System’s ice giants is a necessary prerequisite to identifying them around other stars from the minimal information available (such as mass and radius), and recognizing if those exoplanetary systems contain a type of planet not seen in our Solar System.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Intrinsic magnetic field - understanding the dynamos of our solar system, we would be able to predict the magnetic field strengths and morphologies of exoplanetary dynamos with more confidence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NASA-ESA Ice Giant Study 2016-17</title>
      <link>https://ice-giants.github.io/post/nasa-esa-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 22:04:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ice-giants.github.io/post/nasa-esa-study/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lpi.usra.edu/icegiants/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ice Giants Study&lt;/a&gt; was commissioned by NASA to take a fresh look at science priorities and concepts for missions to the Uranus and Neptune systems in preparation for the third Planetary Science Decadal Survey.  The study team assessed and prioritised science objectives taking into account advances since the last Decadal Survey, current and emerging technologies, mission implementation techniques and celestial mechanics. This study examined a wide range of mission architectures, flight elements, and instruments. Six of the prioritised concepts were studied via JPL’s Team X process and resulting cost estimates were subjected to independent assessment by The Aerospace Corporation.  High-fidelity studies were carried out on four mission architectures:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Neptune orbiter with ~50-kg payload and atmospheric probe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uranus flyby spacecraft with ~50-kg payload and atmospheric probe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uranus orbiter with ~50-kg payload and atmospheric probe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uranus orbiter with ~150-kg payload but without a probe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lpi.usra.edu/icegiants/mission_study/Exec-Summary.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lpi.usra.edu/icegiants/mission_study/Full-Report.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Full Report&lt;/a&gt; are now available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study concluded that &amp;ldquo;The study validated that NASA could likely implement a mission to the ice giants for under $2B (FY15) that would achieve a worthy set of science objectives. Opportunities exist to achieve all priority science objectives for less than $3B. A partnership with another space agency has the potential to significantly increase the science return while limiting the cost to each partner. Given the development time scale of outer solar system missions, the time of the best launch opportunities, and—for Uranus missions—the desire to arrive at the optimal season, now is the time to begin formulating the next mission to the ice giants.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uranus Beyond Voyager 2 - Meudon 2013</title>
      <link>https://ice-giants.github.io/post/meudon-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2013 20:35:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ice-giants.github.io/post/meudon-2013/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In September 2013, Ice Giant scientists from around the globe met at the Observatoire de Paris-Meudon for a conference building on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://uranus.sciencesconf.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;scientific legacy of Voyager 2.&lt;/a&gt;  The audience was composed of about 90 scientists and engineers from 12 countries, interested in the study of this unique planetary system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;purpose-of-meeting&#34;&gt;Purpose of Meeting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the meeting was to review the current knowledge of Uranus from past measurements, to highlight recent advances and ongoing studies on this planetary environment, and summarise the important unsolved scientific questions together with the key measurements required to address them. The meeting culminated in a discussion of the status of future international mission concepts in Europe and in the United States to explore the Uranus System, including updates on feasibility studies and available technologies, together with next Earth-based observing campaigns.  The conclusions of the meeting &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ice-giants/papers/blob/master/2013meudon_uranusmeeting.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;are available to download here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The format of the conference consisted of review and contributed talks on the interior and origins of Uranus, its system of rings and satellites, its atmosphere and ionosphere, its magnetic field and magnetosphere, and on the exploration of the outer heliosphere, with dedicated time for discussion and synthesis. The full &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ice-giants/papers/blob/master/2013meudon_abstracts.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;abstract book is available here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;meeting-outcomes&#34;&gt;Meeting outcomes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scientific and instrumental presentations made clear that Uranus is a top-level priority for several scientific fields. Its extreme planetary, magnetospheric, and heliospheric environments will bring &amp;lsquo;L-class&amp;rsquo; science return in our understanding of fundamental processes operating in our Solar System and beyond. The crucial measurements needed to achieve the study of this system deserve an ambitious space mission, supported by complementary Earth-based observations. With the exception of Neptune, located twice as far away, Uranus remains the only planet not explored by a dedicated orbiting spacecraft. It thus stands as the next step for exploring the solar system, as witnessed by numerous Uranus mission concepts recently proposed to NASA, ESA and CNES calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a community, we strongly support a mission toward Uranus, for which we highly recommend:
* A spacecraft to be planned within the 2020-2030 decade, operating along an orbital tour designed to adequately sample the Uranian environment, with short polar orbits and repeated flybys of the main moons (especially Miranda and Ariel);
* An atmospheric probe and/or aerocapture trajectory to complement remote sensing with in situ measurements;
* and an instrumental payload adequate to fulfil the above key science objectives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Immediate next steps require:
* Feasibility studies to retire risks and develop required technologies for such a mission (phase 0 studies, power supplies such as Radioiosotope Thermoelectric Generators, propulsions modes, optimization of heliospheric measurements during the cruise phase, improved data compression techniques, optimization of telemetry …) ;
* An examination of useful collaborations between national and international space agencies (in particular, lay the groundwork for a multi-agency, Cassini-class Uranus orbiter).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;organising-committee&#34;&gt;Organising committee&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scientific program : N. André, C. Arridge, L.N. Fletcher, D. Gautier, L. Lamy, A. Millilo, M. Hofstadter and M. Tiscareno&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Local organisation : B. Cecconi, C. Briand, D. Gautier, S. Hess, N. Letourneur, L. Lamy, P. Schippers, T. Fouchet, P. Zarka and N. André&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESA&#39;s Call for Large-Class Mission Themes</title>
      <link>https://ice-giants.github.io/post/esa-l2-l3-proposals/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 20:38:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ice-giants.github.io/post/esa-l2-l3-proposals/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In March 2013, the European Space Agency put out a &lt;a href=&#34;http://sci.esa.int/cosmic-vision/51454-call-for-white-papers-for-definition-of-l2-and-l3-missions/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;call for the definition of the next cornerstones of the Cosmic Vision&lt;/a&gt; process, known as L2 and L3.  These missions are planned for launch in 2028 and 2034, respectively, and represent European investments of approximately €1 billion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the recently-selected Jupiter Icy Moons Explorer (JUICE) being developed for the L1 mission (launch in 2022), the planetary science community was urged to actively participate in this call.  There was no shortage of exciting, ambitious and ground-breaking ideas for the exploration of our solar system, addressing themes and questions right at the heart of ESA&amp;rsquo;s Cosmic Vision.  A whole raft of white papers were submitted, several of which were presented at a community meeting in Paris.  Ultimately, an X-ray astronomy mission (ATHENA) and a gravitational wave observatory (LISA) were selected as the cornerstone science themes, but the European Ice Giant community were provided with valuable feedback to continue to seek an international mission to these distant worlds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;senior-survey-committee-report&#34;&gt;Senior Survey Committee Report&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 2013 report of ESA&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://sci.esa.int/cosmic-vision/53261-report-on-science-themes-for-the-l2-and-l3-missions/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Senior Survey Committee&lt;/a&gt; stated:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;In situ exploration of the icy giant planets would bring major advances in our understanding of these worlds in several respects. First, the study of their internal structure (through radio science, accelerometery and, ideally, a measurement of elemental abundances through mass spectrometry aboard a probe), as well as a study of their satellite properties, could provide key diagnostics concerning the history of these systems. Second, an in-depth study of their  atmospheres, ionospheres and magnetospheres, as well as their rings and satellites, will help us understand the physico-chemical processes at work in these two systems. Ideally, comparative planetology could be achieved from similar observations performed on both planets and their environments.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;After the success of the Cassini mission, and after the selection of an exploration mission toward the Jovian system, the exploration of the icy giants appears to be a timely milestone, fully appropriate for an L class mission. The whole planetology community would be involved in the various aspects of this mission, including physics of the interior, atmospheric and surface sciences, plasmas physics and dynamics. Several mission concepts could be considered, including orbiters and probes, and would need to be investigated in the next stage.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The SSC considered the study of the icy giants to be a theme of very high science quality and perfectly fitting the criteria for an L-class mission. However, in view of the competition with a range of other high quality science themes, and despite its undoubted quality, on balance and taking account of the wide array of themes, the SSC does not recommend this theme for L2 or L3. Iview of its importance, however, the SSC recommends that every effort is made to pursue this theme through other means, such as cooperation on missions led by partner agencies.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sci.esa.int/cosmic-vision/52030-white-papers-submitted-in-response-to-esas-call-for-science-themes-for-the-l2-and-l3-missions/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;White papers&lt;/a&gt; relevant to the Ice Giants included:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-science-case-for-an-orbital-mission-to-uranus-exploring-the-origins-of-ice-giant-planets&#34;&gt;The Science Case for an Orbital Mission to Uranus: Exploring the Origins of Ice Giant Planets&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pss.2014.08.009&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Arridge et al. (2014)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ice-giants/papers/blob/master/2013arridge_uranus.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Link to White Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Giant planets helped to shape the conditions we see in the Solar System today and they account for more than 99% of the mass of the Sun&amp;rsquo;s planetary system. They can be subdivided into the Ice Giants (Uranus and Neptune) and the Gas Giants (Jupiter and Saturn), which differ from each other in a number of fundamental ways. Uranus, in particular is the most challenging to our understanding of planetary formation and evolution, with its large obliquity, low self-luminosity, highly asymmetrical internal field, and puzzling internal structure. Uranus also has a rich planetary system consisting of a system of inner natural satellites and complex ring system, five major natural icy satellites, a system of irregular moons with varied dynamical histories, and a highly asymmetrical magnetosphere. Voyager 2 is the only spacecraft to have explored Uranus, with a flyby in 1986, and no mission is currently planned to this enigmatic system. However, a mission to the uranian system would open a new window on the origin and evolution of the Solar System and would provide crucial information on a wide variety of physicochemical processes in our Solar System. These have clear implications for understanding exoplanetary systems. In this paper we describe the science case for an orbital mission to Uranus with an atmospheric entry probe to sample the composition and atmospheric physics in Uranus&amp;rsquo; atmosphere. The characteristics of such an orbiter and a strawman scientific payload are described and we discuss the technical challenges for such a mission. This paper is based on a white paper submitted to the European Space Agency&amp;rsquo;s call for science themes for its large-class mission programme in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;neptune-and-triton-essential-pieces-of-the-solar-system-puzzle&#34;&gt;Neptune and Triton:  Essential Pieces of the Solar System Puzzle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pss.2014.05.008&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Masters et al. 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The planet Neptune and its largest moon Triton hold the keys to major advances across multiple fields of Solar System science. The ice giant Neptune played a unique and important role in the process of Solar System formation, has the most meteorologically active atmosphere in the Solar System (despite its great distance from the Sun), and may be the best Solar System analogue of the dominant class of exoplanets detected to date. Neptune׳s moon Triton is very likely a captured Kuiper Belt object, holding the answers to questions about the icy dwarf planets that formed in the outer Solar System. Triton is geologically active, has a tenuous nitrogen atmosphere, and is predicted to have a subsurface ocean. However, our exploration of the Neptune system remains limited to a single spacecraft flyby, made by Voyager 2 in 1989. Here, we present the high-level science case for further exploration of this outermost planetary system, based on a white paper submitted to the European Space Agency (ESA) for the definition of the second and third large missions in the ESA Cosmic Vision Programme 2015–2025. We discuss all the major science themes that are relevant for further spacecraft exploration of the Neptune system, and identify key scientific questions in each area. We present an overview of the results of a European-led Neptune orbiter mission analysis. Such a mission has significant scope for international collaboration, and is essential to achieve our aim of understanding how the Solar System formed, and how it works today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;scientific-rationale-for-uranus-and-neptune-in-situ-explorations&#34;&gt;Scientific Rationale for Uranus and Neptune in situ Explorations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pss.2017.10.005&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mousis et al., 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1708.00235&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;[Arxiv]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally part of a Saturn probe &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ice-giants/papers/blob/master/2013mousis_probes.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;white paper&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ice giants Uranus and Neptune are the least understood class of planets in our solar system but the most frequently observed type of exoplanets. Presumed to have a small rocky core, a deep interior comprising ∼70% heavy elements surrounded by a more dilute outer envelope of H2 and He, Uranus and Neptune are fundamentally different from the better-explored gas giants Jupiter and Saturn. Because of the lack of dedicated exploration missions, our knowledge of the composition and atmospheric processes of these distant worlds is primarily derived from remote sensing from Earth-based observatories and space telescopes. As a result, Uranus&amp;rsquo;s and Neptune&amp;rsquo;s physical and atmospheric properties remain poorly constrained and their roles in the evolution of the Solar System not well understood. Exploration of an ice giant system is therefore a high-priority science objective as these systems (including the magnetosphere, satellites, rings, atmosphere, and interior) challenge our understanding of planetary formation and evolution. Here we describe the main scientific goals to be addressed by a future in situ exploration of an ice giant. An atmospheric entry probe targeting the 10-bar level, about 5 scale heights beneath the tropopause, would yield insight into two broad themes: i) the formation history of the ice giants and, in a broader extent, that of the Solar System, and ii) the processes at play in planetary atmospheres. The probe would descend under parachute to measure composition, structure, and dynamics, with data returned to Earth using a Carrier Relay Spacecraft as a relay station. In addition, possible mission concepts and partnerships are presented, and a strawman ice-giant probe payload is described. An ice-giant atmospheric probe could represent a significant ESA contribution to a future NASA ice-giant flagship mission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-odinus-mission-concept-the-scientific-case-for-a-mission-to-the-ice-giant-planets-with-twin-spacecrafts-to-unveil-the-history-of-our-solar-system&#34;&gt;The ODINUS Mission Concept:  The Scientific Case for a Mission to the Ice Giant Planets with Twin Spacecrafts to Unveil the History of our Solar System&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1402.2472&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Turrini et al., 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ice-giants/papers/blob/master/2013turrini_ODINUS.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Link to White Paper.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this document is to discuss the scientific case of a space mission to the ice giants Uranus and Neptune and their satellite systems and its relevance to advance our understanding of the ancient past of the Solar System and, more generally, of how planetary systems form and evolve. As a consequence, the leading theme of this proposal will be the first scientific theme of the Cosmic Vision 2015-2025 program: What are the conditions for planetary formation and the emergence of life? In pursuing its goals, the present proposal will also address the second and third scientific theme of the Cosmic Vision 2015-2025 program, i.e.: How does the Solar System work? What are the fundamental physical laws of the Universe? The mission concept we will illustrate in the following will be referred to through the acronym ODINUS, this acronym being derived from its main fields of scientific investigation: Origins, Dynamics and Interiors of Neptunian and Uranian Systems. As the name suggests, the ODINUS mission is based on the use of two twin spacecraft to perform the exploration of the ice giants and their regular and irregular satellites with the same set of instruments. This will allow to perform a comparative study of these two systems so similar and yet so different and to unveil their histories and that of the Solar System.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
