<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homes on Ice Giant Systems 2020</title>
    <link>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homes on Ice Giant Systems 2020</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ice-giants.github.io/home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/slider/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/slider/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic</title>
      <link>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/hero/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/hero/</guid>
      <description>The Best Way to Create the Website You Want from Markdown (or RStudio/Jupyter)
Build Anything with Widgets
Star</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic Kickstart</title>
      <link>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/demo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/demo/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the Academic Kickstart template!
Follow our Getting Started and Page Builder guides to easily personalize the template and then add your own content.
For inspiration, check out the Markdown files which power the personal demo. The easiest way to publish your new site to the internet is with Netlify.
 View the documentation Ask a question Request a feature or report a bug Updating? View the Update Guide and Release Notes Support development of Academic:  Donate a coffee Become a backer on Patreon Decorate your laptop or journal with an Academic sticker Wear the T-shirt    This homepage section is an example of adding elements to the Blank widget.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second Announcement</title>
      <link>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/about/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skills</title>
      <link>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/skills/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Venue</title>
      <link>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/venue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/venue/</guid>
      <description>The first two days (January 20th-21st 2020) of the Ice Giant workshop will take place at the prestigious London home of the Royal Society, in their Wellcome Trust lecture theatre. Advance registration is essential via this link.
Instructions for reaching the Royal Society are available here.
The third day (January 22nd 2020) of the workshop will feature Splinter Sessions hosted at the Learned Institutions of Burlington House (Royal Astronomical Society, Royal Geological Society, and the Linnean Society).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programme</title>
      <link>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/programme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/programme/</guid>
      <description>The Ice Giant Systems workshop will be consist of four distinct components:
 Invited Reviews: Talks at the Royal Society (Monday and Tuesday, January 20th-21st) covering Ice Giant System science (origins, interiors, atmospheres, magnetospheres, satellites, rings), the connections to Exoplanetary science and heliophysics, and potential mission concepts and technologies to enable our future robotic explorers.
 Contributed posters: A dedicated session at the Royal Society on Monday January 20th, showcasing the latest research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Registration and Abstracts</title>
      <link>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/registration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/registration/</guid>
      <description>Registration for the Royal Society plenary sessions (January 20th and 21st 2020) and the Splinter Workshops (January 22nd 2020) are now open.
 Plenary Registration: The two-day plenary sessions are free to attend, but advance registration is essential via this link.
 Splinter Registration: Registration for the splinter workshops on January 22nd at Burlington House is via a separate process using this link - a £55 fee will be charged to cover the costs of venue hire and catering (refreshments and lunch will be provided).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience</title>
      <link>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/experience/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accomplish&amp;shy;ments</title>
      <link>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/accomplishments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/accomplishments/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited Speakers</title>
      <link>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/invitees/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/invitees/</guid>
      <description> January 20th 2020:  Ravit Helled, University of Zurich (Origins of the Ice Giants) Jonathan Fortney, UC Santa Cruz (Interiors of Ice Giants) Ricardo Hueso, University of Bilbao (Atmospheric Dynamics and Clouds) Julianne Moses, Space Science Institute (Atmospheric Chemistry) Henrik Melin, University of Leicester (Upper Atmosphere and Ionosphere) Krista Soderlund, University of Texas (Ice Giant Dynamos) Carol Paty, University of Oregon (Ice Giant Magnetospheres) Laurent Lamy, Observatoire de Paris Meudon (Ice Giant Auroras) Mark Showalter, SETI Institute (Rings of Uranus and Neptune) Elizabeth Turtle, APL, Maryland (Satellites of Uranus) Michele Bannister, Queens University Belfast (Triton and the KBO Connection) Poster Session 17:00-18:15  January 21st 2020:  Heidi Hammel, Space Science Institute (A Voyager Retrospective) TBD (The Exoplanetary Perspective) Abigail Rymer, APL, Maryland (The Heliophysics Perspective) Mark Hofstadter, JPL (US Perspectives on Ice Giant Missions) TBD (European Perspectives on Ice Giant Missions) John Elliot, JPL (Mission Design Prospects) Tom Spilker, JPL (Enabling Technologies for Ice Giants) Richard Ambrosi, University of Leicester (Space Nuclear Power) Discussion: Strategies for Ice Giant Missions in the 2020s  January 22nd 2020:  Splinter Sessions  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local Information</title>
      <link>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/local-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/local-info/</guid>
      <description>Details on accommodation and transport during your stay in London.
Instructions for reaching the Royal Society are available here. Information about Burlington House (for the splinter meetings) is available here, and the nearest Underground stations are Green Park and Piccadilly Circus.
Hotels London accommodation can be expensive, so you are advised to book early. The following list of hotels provide good value for money, but the organisers take no responsibility for the quality of the accommodation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organisers</title>
      <link>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/organisers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/organisers/</guid>
      <description>Leigh Fletcher (University of Leicester) Adam Masters (Imperial College) Ian Cohen (Applied Physics Laboratory) Amy Simon (Goddard Space Flight Center) Mark Hofstadter (Jet Propulsion Laboratory) Athena Coustenis (Observatoire de Paris Meudon) Chris Arridge (Lancaster University) Kathleen Mandt (Applied Physics Laboratory)  Along with advice and guidance from Diego Turrini, Laurent Lamy, David Atkinson, Pontus Brandt, Olivier Witasse, Olivier Mousis, and Abigail Rymer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent Posts</title>
      <link>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/posts/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/projects/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organisers</title>
      <link>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/people/</guid>
      <description>Scientific Organising Committee: * Leigh Fletcher (University of Leicester) * Adam Masters (Imperial College) * Ian Cohen (Applied Physics Laboratory) * Amy Simon (Goddard Spaceflight Center) * Mark Hofstadter (Jet Propulsion Laboratory)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks</title>
      <link>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/talks/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Featured Publications</title>
      <link>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/featured/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/featured/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent Publications</title>
      <link>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/publications/</guid>
      <description> Quickly discover relevant content by filtering publications.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Popular Topics</title>
      <link>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/tags/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/tags/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ice-giants.github.io/home/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>