<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Ice Giant Systems 2020</title>
    <link>https://ice-giants.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Ice Giant Systems 2020</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 20:22:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ice-giants.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>First Announcement</title>
      <link>https://ice-giants.github.io/post/first-announcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 20:22:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ice-giants.github.io/post/first-announcement/</guid>
      <description>##First Announcement: Ice Giant Systems 2020. PLEASE SAVE THE DATE ##January 20th-22nd 2020, Royal Society, London.
Overview: New and ambitious missions to the distant Ice Giants and their satellites will become a key element of our Solar System exploration in the coming decades. The planetary community is warmly invited to attend an international conference on Ice Giant exploration at the Royal Society in London.
Format: The meeting will consist of two days of invited plenary talks and a third day of splinter workshops, aiming to showcase the cutting edge of Ice Giant system research and the rationale for a return to Uranus and Neptune.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ice Giant Media Coverage</title>
      <link>https://ice-giants.github.io/post/ice-giant-media-coverage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 20:21:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ice-giants.github.io/post/ice-giant-media-coverage/</guid>
      <description>Media Coverage: Missions to the Ice Giants</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Entry Probes Meeting</title>
      <link>https://ice-giants.github.io/post/marseille-in-situ-probes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 21:35:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ice-giants.github.io/post/marseille-in-situ-probes/</guid>
      <description>In Situ Exploration of the Ice Giants</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COSPAR Ice Giants 2018</title>
      <link>https://ice-giants.github.io/post/cospar-ice-giants-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 21:50:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ice-giants.github.io/post/cospar-ice-giants-2018/</guid>
      <description>COSPAR Symposium B5.4 – Wednesday July 18th 2018 Ice Giant Systems: New Results and Future Exploration MSO: Leigh Fletcher (Univ. of Leicester) DSO: Amy Simon (Goddard Spaceflight Center)
COSPAR sub-commission B5 hosted several symposia focussing on the exploration of the outer solar system at the 2018 COSPAR meeting in Pasadena, ranging from the highlights of past missions (Cassini), active missions (Juno), and future missions (exploration of ocean worlds). The ice giant community met on Wednesday afternoon to focus on the exploration of Uranus and Neptune, from their interiors, to their atmospheres, magnetospheres, rings and satellite systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NASA-ESA Ice Giant Study 2016-17</title>
      <link>https://ice-giants.github.io/post/nasa-esa-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 22:04:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ice-giants.github.io/post/nasa-esa-study/</guid>
      <description>The Ice Giants Study was commissioned by NASA to take a fresh look at science priorities and concepts for missions to the Uranus and Neptune systems in preparation for the third Planetary Science Decadal Survey. The study team assessed and prioritised science objectives taking into account advances since the last Decadal Survey, current and emerging technologies, mission implementation techniques and celestial mechanics. This study examined a wide range of mission architectures, flight elements, and instruments.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>